SUMMARY

I am a passionate Full Stack Developer, who has been recently focused on Node, Express, Nextjs, React, Docker and contributing where I can to open source. Additionally, I possess a mindset for high drive, continuous improvement, and dedication to quality work. I am excited to work for an organization that instills best coding practices and motivates and encourages inquisitive minds.

SKILLS

- REST/RPC API's
- CI/CD
- Octalysis Gamification Framework
- E-commerce
- Java
- MongoDB, MYSQL, MSSQL
- Express
- Nextis
- Javascript
- Webpack
- Babel

- Web scraping
- 12 Factor App & SOLID principles
- Lighthouse audit inquirer
- WordPress
- Shopify
- Jenkins
- AWS
- Docker
- Cloud Foundry
- Pair Programming Etiquette

EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Developer / Allstate Insurance - Chicago, IL

01/2019 - Current

- Developing internal systems to provide secure application deployment across the enterprise utilizing modern web frameworks, standards and security practices.
- Tech Utilized: java, spring boot, JPA, JUnit, Mockito, PowerMockito, react, redux, react-router, normalizer, jest, enzyme, fetch-mock, node, express, super-test, Docker, Jenkins, Cloud Foundry, Kibana, Graphana/Prometheus, MS Suite
- Actively engage in TDD and XP practices.
- Write both Unit and Integration/End to End testing.
- Follow best practices with regards to CI/CD deployments.
- Writing scalable and maintainable code following 12 factor and SOLID principles.
- Monolith and Microservice based applications/systems.
- Integrate with a variety of 3rd party APIs including: Veracode, Whitesource, Contrast, Twistlock, Nexpose/Rapid7,
 VersionOne, MS Teams

Director of Development / Youtech and Associates - Naperville, IL

06/2018 - 01/2019

- Managed a team of 7 developers both local and remote
- Workflow standardization; including git, code reviews, and testing
- Conducted meetings on both a team and personal level

- Analyzed employees' skill levels and implemented new techniques to boost staff knowledge.
- Personal & professional development of team through promoting sponsored events and lightning talks/lunch and learns
- Maintained and grew new and existing client relationships via guick and effective communication and providing detailed explanations of expectations.

Full-Stack Developer / Youtech And Associates - Naperville, IL

09/2017 - 06/2018

- Independently planned, prioritized, and executed development of complex custom web and mobile applications.
- Tech Utilized: Node, Express, EJS, Angular 2+, RxJS, NativeScript, MongoDB, Mongoose, MYSQL, MSSQL, Magento, WordPress, Shopify
- Interfaced with external and internal clients from design to marketing to C-suite executives and stakeholders on project needs and status.
- Troubleshot WordPress and Magento third party plugin/extension installation con icts/incompatibilities
- Created custom WordPress and Magento plugin/extensions.

Lead Web Developer / The Difference Engine - Chicago, IL

05/2017 - 08/2017

- Provided a full stack e-commerce solution for a non-profit coffee subscription startup.
- Tech Utilized: Ruby on Rails, React, rspec, Stripe, Devise, SendGrid Developed admin workspace, responsive cart, and database architecture.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Actualize - Chicago, IL 05/2017

Bootcamp: Full-Stack Development

EXTRAS

- I enjoy playing with Arduino and Raspberry Pi's, Guitar, and working on side projects that further my understanding of web development related topics.
- 2019 T4Youth Ping Pong tournament competitor for Allstate
- Chicago Golden Gloves competitor